Will come back early in the course they talked about building a skyscraper a skyscraper could be a project
would be a really big project.
When you consider all the different moving parts.
So we have you know the foundation of that skyscraper the excavation of the metal's deal with the steel
beams and the framing there and the glass the elevators the interior all of the different things that
go into building a skyscraper just mind boggling how all that comes together.
So that could be a project it would be a really big project.
More likely though it would be a program a program where we have multiple related projects that are
managed in orchestration to receive benefits that you would not receive if each project were managed
independent of one another.
So if you think about that skyscraper being a program you can think about the coordination that would
have to happen between all of those different components.
So a program would be one big umbrella if you will of all of those projects and the program manager
would work with the project managers to orchestrate that coordination.
So you think about the delivery of materials.
There's only so much space on that job site for the materials.
So there has to be some logistics there.
And you think about the different resources that are needed electricians that are needed at different
points in that project and at different places in the project.
So the orchestration I keep saying that word because that's really what it is it's managing all of these
different projects with the project managers to receive benefits by scheduling coordinating using logistics
getting to work with one another.
That's program management.
And so Program Management is a related area of project management programs have projects you know project
managers and you have program managers.
So there are multiple related areas.
There is a certification it's a pretty tough certification for program management from PMI.
It's the GMP the program management professional.
There's not a lot of people around the world that have this certification so program management.
The PGE Pete just want to be able to recognize and be familiar with that idea of programs that programs
have projects.
All right.
Good job.
Keep moving forward.